Here, I'll step through the code for
在这里 我将介绍
the simple mover node and explain what's happening at each step of the way.
这个简单的 mover 节点的代码 并解释每一步发生的事情
Rospy is the official Python client library for ROS.
Rospy 是 ROS 的官方 Python 客户端库
It provides most of the fundamental functionality
它提供了大部分
required for interfacing with ROS via Python.
通过 Python 与 ROS 进行交互所需的基本功能
It has tools for creating nodes interfacing with topics,
它拥有创建与主题交互的节点的工具
services, parameters, and more.
服务、参数等等
It will certainly be worth your time to check out
因此 务必花时间去看看
the Rospy API documentation and the links below.
Rospy API 文档和下面的链接
General information about rospy,
关于 rospy 的一般信息
including other tutorials may be found on the ROS wiki.
包括可以在 ROS 维基上找到的其他教程
First off, from the standard messages package,
首先 从标准消息包中
we import Float64, which is one of the primitive message types in ROS.
我们导入 Float64 它是 ROS 中的一种原始消息类型
This package also contains all of the other primitive types.
该软件包还包含了所有其他基元类型
Later on in this script,
稍后 在这个脚本中
we will be publishing a Float64 message to the position command topics for each joint.
我们将发布 Float64 消息到每个联合的位置命令主题
At the top of the mover function,
在 mover 函数开始
two publishers are declared.
声明了两个发布者
One for joint one commands,
一个用于 joint one 命令
and one for joint two commands.
一个用于 joint two 命令
Here, the queue size parameter is used to determine the maximum number of
这里 队列大小参数用于确定消息丢弃之前
messages that may be stored in the publisher before messages are dropped.
发布者可以存储的最大消息数量
More information about this parameter can be found in the links below.
有关此参数的更多信息 请查看下面的链接
Here, I'm initializing a client node and registering it with the master.
这里 我正在初始化客户机节点并向主机注册
Our mover is the name of the node,
Mover 是节点的名称
and the init node function must be called before
并且必须先调用 init 节点函数
any other Rospy package functions are called.
然后才能调用任何其他 Rospy 包函数
On line 13, the rate object is created.
在第 13 行 创建了速率对象 rate
And here, we set it with a value of 10 hertz.
在这里 我们将其设置为 10 赫兹
Rates are used to limit the frequency at which certain loops spin in ROS.
速率用于限制某些环路在 ROS 中旋转的频率
Choosing a rate which is too high may result in unnecessarily high CPU usage,
选择太高的速率可能会导致不必要的高 CPU 使用率
while choosing a rate that's too low could result in high overall system latency.
而选择过低的速率可能会导致整个系统的高延迟
Choosing sensible values for all of the nodes in a ROS system is a bit of a fine art.
为 ROS 系统中的所有节点选择合理的值是一种艺术
Start time is used to determine how much time has elapsed.
开始时间用于确定已经过了多长时间
When using ROS with simulated time,
当使用模拟时间操作 ROS 时
as we're doing here,
就行我们现在这样
rospy.time.now will initially return
Rospy.time.now 最初将返回
zero until the first message has been received on the clock topic.
零 直到在时钟主题上收到第一条消息
This is why start time is set and pulled continuously until a non-zero value is returned.
这就是为什么 开始时间被设定并持续拉动 直到返回非零值
Here, we have the main loop due to the call to rate.sleep,
在这里 由于调用 rate.sleep 我们有 main 循环
the loop is traversed at approximately 10 hertz.
循环遍历速度大约为 10 赫兹
Each trip through the body of the loop will result
每次通过循环体将会导致
in two joint command messages being published.
发布两条关节命令消息
The joint angles are sampled from a sine wave with a period of 10 seconds
关节角度以 10 秒的周期从正弦波中采样
and in magnitude from negative pi over two to positive pi over two.
振幅为负二分之一 π 到正二分之一 π
When the node receives the signal to shut down,
当节点收到关闭信号时
either from the master,
无论是来自主机
or via SIGINT via the console window,
还是通过控制台窗口的 SIGINT
the loop will be exited and the program will continue.
都会退出循环 并且程序将继续
Here, if the name variable is set to main
这里 如果 name 变量被设置为 main
indicating that this script is being executed directly,
以表明该脚本正在直接执行
the mover function will be called.
则 mover 函数将被调用
The try-except blocks here are significant as Rospy uses exceptions extensively.
当 Rospy 广泛使用异常时 这里的 try-except 代码部分很重要
The particular exception being caught here is the ROS interrupt exception.
这里捕捉到的特殊异常是 ROS 中断异常
This exception is raised when the node has been signaled for shut down.
当节点已收到关闭信号时 会引发此异常
If there was perhaps some sort of cleanup needing to be done
如果在节点关闭之前 需要进行一些清理工作
before the node shuts down, it would be done here.
清理将在这里完成
More information about Rospy exceptions can be found in the links below.
有关 Rospy 异常的更多信息 请查看下面的链接
Assuming that your work space has recently been
假设你的工作空间
built and it's setup.bash has been sourced,
刚刚建立 而且它的 setup.bash 已经完成
you can launch simple arm as follows.
你可以按如下方式启动简单机器臂
Once the ROS master,
一旦 ROS 主进程
gazebo and all of our relevant nodes are up and running,
Gazebo 和所有的相关节点都正常运行
we can finally launch the simple mover node.
我们就启动 simple mover 节点了
All right,
好的
and here's what it should look like.
结果应该大致这样
Congratulations. You've now written your first ROS node.
祝贺你！ 你已经完成了的第一个ROS节点